newsinc.com 2015-05-28

# | NDN

Last modified:  September 6, 2013 (view archived versions)

This Privacy Policy explains the data collection and use practices of News Distribution Network, Inc. and its affiliates (“NDN”) on the NDN player (the “NDN Player”) and on NDN’s websites: [www.newsinc.com](http://www.newsinc.com/) and [www.politicaliq.com](http://www.politicaliq.com/) (together with the NDN Player, hereafter the “Websites”).  By using the Websites, you acknowledge that you have read and understood our Privacy Policy.

We are committed to protecting your privacy and honoring the integrity of your personal information. We do not use any information collected through the Websites for purposes other than as disclosed in this Privacy Policy. If you have any questions concerning how we process your personal information or any other queries with regard to this Privacy Policy please contact our support team by email at [privacy@newsinc.com](mailto:privacy@newsinc.com) or via mail to News Distribution Network, Inc.

## 1\. What this Privacy Policy Covers

  * This Privacy Policy applies to the manner in which your personal information is processed when using the services offered by NDN via the Websites and other features, content or applications offered from time to time by NDN in connection with the Websites. The Websites are hosted in the United States.
  * This Privacy Policy covers how NDN collects, uses and shares information, including personally identifiable information that you provide to us and information we collect automatically related to your use of the Websites and services.
  * This Privacy Policy does not apply to the way in which your personal information is processed by non-NDN companies who are not otherwise owned, operated or controlled by NDN, including the processing of personal information which is not controlled by NDN, or acts of other third parties.

## 2\. Information Collection

When you visit the Websites, you provide us with three types of information: (1) personally identifiable information and other information about you that you knowingly choose to disclose, (2) information we collect automatically as you interact with the Websites, and (3) information we collect from other sources.

## 3\. Information You Provide to NDN

We collect personal information from you when you submit questions or material to us, register on the Websites, purchase a product from us, email us, enter one of our contests or sweepstakes, or use the Websites, such as setting up your personal profile, making connections, sending messages, performing searches and queries, forming or joining groups, submitting content, participating in discussions and forums, or sending and receiving information through various channels.

We use personal information collected through the Websites to:

  * provide a personalized service,
  * conduct market research surveys,
  * fulfill product orders,
  * run features that incorporate submissions to the Websites,
  * provide information and services you request or subscribe to, and
  * provide you with information about, and access to, products and services we offer, either ourselves or jointly with or on behalf of other organizations.

If you do not wish to receive information about our products or services, or the products or services offered jointly with or on behalf of other organizations, please check the appropriate box on the registration page or other relevant form or page through which the information is collected.

## 4\. Automatically Collected Information

We may collect and/or process information through the use of cookies and internet protocol (“IP”) addresses, such as demographic information and browsing patterns, including the domain and host from which you access the internet, your domain name, the IP address of the computer you are using, the name of the page that referred you to us, the date and times you enter and exit the Websites, the pages you visit before and after visiting the Websites, the web pages, video content and advertisements you view and links you click on within the Websites, unique identifiers, including mobile device identification numbers that can identify the physical location of such devices in accordance with applicable law, and information collected through web beacons and other technologies. We also collect information about your interactions and transactions with us and some of our business partners. Such information does not identify any individual and will not be linked to any personal information. We use such information to:

  * monitor the usage of the Websites,
  * build up marketing profiles,
  * aid strategic development,
  * manage our relationship with advertisers and content providers, and
  * audit usage of the Websites.

We may share such information, in the aggregate form only, with our affiliates, partners or advertisers, or other third parties.

## 5\. Information Collected from Other Sources

Where permitted by law, we may collect information about you from other sources, including through interactive applications (such as mobile devices, third-party services and embedded video players), from co-branded partners and sites and from commercially available sources (such as data aggregators and public databases). The following are examples of information we may collect from other sources:

  * demographic data, such as age, gender, and income level,
  * publicly-observed data, such as activities on blogs, videos, and other online postings,
  * your interests and purchase behavior, and
  * other navigation data, such as web sites visited and advertisements viewed or clicked on.

## 6\. Use of Information

In addition to the uses described above with respect to information you provide and information we automatically collect, we use collected information to customize the advertising and content you see, fulfill your requests for products and services, improve our services, contact you if necessary, conduct research, assist with systems administration, resolve problems, provide anonymous reporting for internal and external clients, and prevent potentially prohibited or illegal activities and otherwise in accordance with our Terms of Use. We may occasionally use your name and email address to send you notifications regarding new services we offer that we think you may find valuable. We may combine information about you that we have with information we obtain from business partners or other companies. We may also create compilations of information that are not personally-identifying and provide these compilations to other companies to help them understand the shopping patterns or general interests of visitors to the Websites.

## 7\. Use of Cookies

We use cookies, tags and similar technologies to recognize your preferences and effectively and efficiently administer the Websites. We use the information we collect to enhance your visit to the Websites and provide you with information tailored to your interests. The information collected on our behalf does not contain your name, address, email address or any other personally identifiable information. You may elect to refuse or delete cookies, however, doing so may affect your use of some portions of the Websites and the services NDN provides.

We use third-party tracking and advertising providers such as Auditude and Quantcast to act on our behalf. The third-party tracking and advertising technology that we use on the Websites uses information derived from your visits to the Websites to target advertising to the Websites. In addition, our advertisers may use other third-party advertising technology to target advertising on the Websites and other sites. They may track and analyze your usage of the Websites through the use of cookies, pixel tags, web beacons and similar technologies. They may collect and share with us usage information about visits to the Websites and use of the NDN services. They also may measure and research the effectiveness of our advertisements, track page usage and paths followed during and after your use of the Websites and the NDN services, help us target the advertisements on the Websites, and track use of our advertisements and other links from marketing partners' sites to the NDN services.

To “opt-out” of such third-party cookies, go to <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/> and select Collective, Quantcast, YuMe, Specific Media and ValueClick Media as your opt out choices.

For detailed information on the cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them see our Cookie Policy.

## 8\. Disclosure of Information

NDN is committed to maintaining your trust and we want you to understand when and with whom we may share information collected about you.

  * Authorized third-party service providers. We share your information with third-party vendors who help us with specialized services, including customer support, email and text message deployment, business analytics, marketing, and data processing. These third parties are allowed to use your information to help us provide our services and not for any other purpose.
  * Business transfers. We may share your information in connection with a substantial corporate transaction, such as the sale of an NDN company, a merger, consolidation, asset sale (including the sale of a NDN Website) or in the unlikely event of bankruptcy.
  * Legal requirements. We may disclose information about our users, including contact information, to respond to subpoenas, court orders, legal process, and other law enforcement measures, and to comply with other applicable legal obligations.
  * Protect our Websites and users. We may disclose information to protect and defend the legal rights, interests, and safety of NDN Websites, other NDN companies, and their employees, agents, and contractors (including enforcing our agreements), to protect the safety and security of users of the Websites and members of the public, and as otherwise disclosed in our Terms of Use.

## 9\. Submissions

Any personal information you choose to provide to us with your submissions posted to this site may appear on the site, but only to identify you as the author of the submission, unless you expressly authorize us to make further use of the information on the site. If you voluntarily disclose or permit disclosure of personal information, that information can also be collected and used by others. If you submit to the site any comments, photographs, videos, music, text or other content, you grant to NDN the unlimited, perpetual, royalty-free right to use your name, voice, likeness and other personal information in connection with such submission in any media, now known or hereafter devised, throughout the world.

## 10\. Privacy Policy for Children Under 13

In accordance with the US Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (commonly referred to as “COPPA”) and any other equivalent or analogous legislation, we do not require children under the age of 13 to provide us with any more information than is reasonably necessary to participate and make use of this site and under no circumstances do we require children under the age of 13 to provide us with any personal information.  Children under the age of 13 should not submit or post any personal information without the written consent of their parents or legal guardians. If you are a child under the age of 13 and want to submit your personal information to us, you should ask your parents to send an email to [privacy@newsinc.com](mailto:privacy@newsinc.com) specifically allowing us to collect your personal information through this site. By doing so, you allow us to alert your parent or guardian about the Websites’ Privacy Policy.  We do not intend to sell, license or trade any such information collected to third parties.  Parents may review or change the personal information of their children provided to us or further refuse our collection of such information by sending an email to [privacy@newsinc.com](mailto:privacy@newsinc.com).

## 11\. Partner Sites / Linked Sites

Our site features several activities, which are co-sponsored or operated by other sites. These activities will be identifiable by their co-branding. While these activities originate on the Websites, they may link to other sites not operated by NDN. This Privacy Policy does not cover the practices of third parties, including those that may disclose information to NDN.  We have no control over the privacy practices or the content of any of our co-sponsors and strongly recommend that you check their privacy policies before engaging in these activities. You may be asked to provide information about yourself to register for a service offered by a co-branded partner. In doing so, you may be providing your information to both us and the co-branded partner, or we may share your information with the co-branded partner. Additionally, our site contains links to other sites, including those of advertisers. We have no control over the privacy practices of advertisers or other sites to which we provide links from this site. For example, if you click on a banner advertisement, the click takes you off this site. These other sites may use cookies, collect data or solicit personal information. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. We strongly recommend that you check the applicable privacy policy of the site to which you are linking especially before submitting any personally identifiable information.

## 12\. Security of Information

We use commercially reasonable efforts to keep your personally identifiable information secure. Unfortunately, no electronic communication over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. While we strive to take care to protect your personally identifiable information, NDN cannot warrant the security of any information that you submit to us, and you do so at your own risk. We do offer secured-server transactions that encrypt your information in transit to thwart someone from intercepting it and misusing it when collecting credit card information for online purchases. We also store any personal information, including credit card numbers, in a secure area to which the general public does not have access.

## 13\. Transfer of Data Internationally

NDN is headquartered in the United States. Please be aware that information you provide to us or we obtain as a result of your use of the Websites may be collected in your country and subsequently transferred to the United States or another country in accordance with applicable law. The privacy and data protection laws in another country may not be equivalent to such laws in your country of residence. By using and participating in the Websites or providing us with your information, you consent to the collection, international transfer, storage, and processing of your information.

## 14\. Updating Personal Information and Your Rights

If you would like to change any contact or billing information, or if you no longer desire to receive any marketing communications from NDN or our partners, please email us at [privacy@newsinc.com](mailto:privacy@newsinc.com).  You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data or email communications we may send to you from time to time. Please note that we may need to retain some information about you in order to satisfy our legal and security obligations. For example, some of your information may remain in back-up storage even if you ask us to delete it. In some cases, you may be entitled under local laws to access or object to the processing of information that we hold relating to you.

## 15\. Access to Your Information

In accordance with certain European data protection laws, you have the right to access information held about you by us. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with applicable laws. Any access request may be subject to a small fee to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

## 16\. Changes in Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time, and will post any changes as soon as they go into effect without prior notice to you. Any such changes are effective as of the date such changes are posted on this page, and where appropriate we may notify you by email.  Your continued usage after such changes are posted constitutes acceptance of each revised Privacy Policy. Please check this page periodically to view our most current Privacy Policy.
